Udoka Kenneth Nkwocha

♦ http://udoka.me/ ■ writeudo@gmail.com ♦ /udokah 🛅 /thisisudo

Passionate about learning and building stuff for the web. Able to understand business requirements, prioritise work based on highest business value and work with teams to solve problems.

In-depth knowledge of JavaScript and web technologies. Experience building RESTful API's on the backend with NodeJS, MySQL & MongoDB.

Feb 2015 - Feb 2016

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

Relevant Experience

Software Engineer (Frontend) at Zalando SE Feb 2017 - Present

Working on tools to increase developer productivity while experimenting with Micro-services for frontend.

Redux NodeJS React SCSS Javascript ES6 **AppDynamics Google Analytics** S zalando.de Webpack

Software Developer at Andela

Built apps to track and manage the placement of developers on client engagment. Built an internal app integrated with Slack to manage the usage of available laundry machines. I also helped support Andela's Now We Give initiative, a program that offers to build websites for clients in exchange for charitable donations.

AngularJS NodeJS Firebase MongoDB Ruby On Rails CSS3 **PostgreSQL** sandela.com **Javascript**

Frontend Developer at Botosoft Tech LTD

Onsite consulting. I worked closely with UI designers to create awesome user interfaces offering an intuitive user experience. My roles involved tranforming designs and sketches to semantic HTML/CSS code equivalent.

HTML5 CSS3 Javascript jQuery www.botosoft.com Front-End Developer at virtualQ GMBH

Feb 2016 - Jan 2017

Migrated core company products - dashboards and 3rd party embeddable widgets - from Ruby (Rails) to Javascript (React) while supporting multiple languages English and German. Created charts using D3 provide more insights to customers.

NodeJS React [Redux] SCSS D3 Svirtualq.io

Full-stack Developer at UDCreate LTD

Jan 2013 - Feb 2015

Remote/Onsite consulting for tools & apps owned by small and medium scale businesses. Built & maintained over 15+ projects for happy clients.

Apache Linux MySQL PHP | Java Android CSS3 jQuery Bootstrap Javascript **udoka.me**

Mar 2012 - Aug 2013 Full-stack Developer (Intern) at SME Funds

Built marketing website, developed customer dashboard to signup customers, track referrals and generate customer reports. Also developed mini-ecommerce tool for customers.

MySQL PHP Linux Apache Javascript | CSS3 [jQuery] [Bootstrap] www.smefunds.com

Education

University of Nigeria Nnsukka

2009 - 2013

Degree in Computer Science and Education, final year project a result management application.

Selected Personal Projects

Tweet Threader Naija Phone Number 2017 2017 A fast minimal NPM module to validate Nigerian mobile phone Simple app to create threaded tweets on Twitter experimenting with numbers using Regular Expressions. Javascript ES6's Generators and Promises. NodeJS React Redux SCSS Javascript ES6 **S** tweet-threader Javascript] Regular Expressions NPM naija-phone-number **Event Calendar** LaundryApp & Bot 2015 2016 An app integrated with a Slack bot to manage laundry machine A simple app to manage calendar events. usage, scheduling and notification for multiple registered laundry AngularJS Sevent-calendar-app CSS3 Boostrap Javascript machine users. Ruby Rails PostgreSQL jQuery Javascript **♦ LaundryApp**

Frogger Game

Javascript

2015 **Browser Drawing App** 2015

A simple browser based game built just for fun.

HTML5 Canvas

A simple browser based drawing app built to learn more about HTML5 Canvas.

CSS3 HTML5 Canvas S drawing-app **Javascript**

Selected Awards

Google Developer Groups (GDG) Lagos Hackathon

2014

Built an app that allowed multiple people save money together in a digital wallet to fund a common goal.

⑤ frogger-fame